What just happened?
Kawachi
Yeah. Right.
I was just about to get up.
Really? Okay.
Stop worrying already.
We'll begin negotiations with them next week, okay?
Later.
Last night, my grandfather on my mother's side passed away.
Were the people in that dream...
...Granddad and Mum?
Apparently, he had fallen out of touch with his relatives.
Geez. The first time I've been back
here in forever, and it's for a funeral.
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
I'm here.
Oh, Daikichi. You're early.
You can leave your bag in Granddad's room.
Right.
By the way, I saw a girl in the garden...
I don't remember her. Did Haruko's kid look like that?
That isn't Reina-chan.
Then whose kid is she?
Geez. This kitchen is so awkward...
What should I do now?
He went pretty peacefully for someone who lived to be 79.
Apparently, that girl is your grandfather's illegitimate child.
Huh!?
Granddad's kid!?
He never told me anything about that!
And apparently, his lover took off, too.
Lover? The guy was 79, right?
It's so embarrassing and shameful.
Then that makes her your little sister, right?
And my aunt, I guess.
It's not a joke!
You're thirty years old now! Try to be a bit more sensitive!
You went peacefully, didn't you, Granddad?
How much should I give?
That's entirely up to you. Give as much or as little as you wish.
But surely, you must expect a certain amount.
Really, however much you wish to give would be appreciated.
Though the custom these days is to
have some Buddhist scriptures read...
...and a posthumous Buddhist name conferred on the dead.
She said it'd cost between 400,000 and 500,000 yen.
That's a fair amount.
Hello. It's been a long time.
Oh, Daikichi. It's been a while.
Have you been keeping busy?
Well, yeah...
Too busy to make time for his dear mother, who longs to see him.
Didn't even make it back for New Year.
Wait, Reina!
Hey, Reina!
Haruko!
Oh, Dai-chan. It's been a while.
Mum!
Reina!
Got you!
Be a good girl and sit quietly, okay?
Don't want to!
What is it?
Nothing...
You really are just like your grandfather.
Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, Mum told me before.
I wonder.
I'm sure my brother was lonely, since he lived on his own, but...
Apparently, they found a Baby Book...
...with the name "Rin" in it.
But pulling something like that at the age of 79...?
Well, putting aside whether or not he's her father,
you've got to hand it to the old guy.
Daikichi, can you get the cushions out of the closet?
What do you want?
Hey, hey!
I'll trade you!
No! Leave it like that.
I did it!
Hey! Look, look!
Reina, don't run around!
Well done!
Is it pretty?
Of course! You're awfully good at cat's cradle, Reina-chan!
Try and do a four step ladder next!
My, my. Reina-chan... Pass it to me a moment.
Poo bomb!
Stop that, Reina!
Uncle. Uncle!
You should go to sleep.
I'll handle watching the incense for a bit.
Right.
Hey, don't sleep there!
I'll go sleep in the other room then.
What about the incense?
Daikichi says he'd keep an eye on it.
Come on!
Keep an eye on my brother, okay?
You should go and sleep, too.
I'm fine.
You look awful.
Kaga Souichi
Well, then, everyone.
Please say your last good-byes.
Say hello to your mother for me.
Granddad...
I'll see you soon enough.
Reina, time to go.
Coming!
It's time to say good-bye to Granddad.
Okay.
A field of flowers!
Stop that!
No! I'm going to make a field of flowers!
I want to make one!
You should come and say good-bye, too.
Put these on Granddad.
Hey!
Bellflowers...
TL Note: In Japanese, bellflowers are 'Rindou'.
Granddad's favourite flowers...
He'd be happiest with these flowers, right?
Is he never going to wake up?
Yeah. He'll never wake up again.
You really are his kid, aren't you?
Mother and Child Health Record
So what happened to this "Yoshii Masako"?
I don't think tracking down someone who abandoned their child...
...will really lead to much good.
How irresponsible.
And my brother stubbornly refused to say a word about it, too.
Watch it!
That girl can't talk!
She's such a pain.
And she hasn't even lost her baby teeth!
She can, too!
And she's not a pain!
She can't talk!
So I'm so bored!
Here. Take them all and go away!
You're like an owner of a sweet shop.
Sorry, Dai-chan.
Never mind any long-term plans,
who's going to take care of her now?
I can't. We have a shop to run.
If she were just a little less strange...
And it looks like she hasn't even started to speak yet.
Mum, you're at home all the time.
Can't you take her for a bit?
T-There's no way I can do that!
I don't have the time for something like that!
Do you even know how difficult it is to raise a child?
And how much I've already sacrificed?
If you can't properly take care of her, it'd be less cruel to not bother at all.
Aren't we supposed to be finding somebody to take her?
It's not like you're planning to do anything yourself, Onii-chan.
Try to look at things a bit more realistically.
Besides, we don't even know whether she really is Granddad's child.
Nothing to say, right? Bet you haven't even thought it through.
For now,
I suggest contacting a facility that will take her off our hands immediately.
What?
Rin!
Want to come stay with me?
Hey, Daikichi!
Onii-chan!
Gramps, I'm hungry.
G-Gramps?
Don't call me that!
You're the one who's my aunt!
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Is it good?
Yeah.
Seconds?
There's nothing left to go with the rice.
I'll make rice balls.
I don't have the tools to make them, either.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey! It's still hot!
Hey, look!
But it'll have a gentle flavour.
Here you go, Gramps!
Sorry. Daikichi!
"Daikichi" sounds weird, too.
It's good.